Liang Zhang

626-215-3962 titanzhang@gmail.com 2870 N. Towne Ave., Apt#48, Pomona, CA 91767

Profile

I'v been working in the internet industry for 10+ years and have rich experiences in a variety of web site related technologies, which spread from web page to database, coding to web site operating, traditional programming languages to contemporary ones.

Experience

DIRECTOR OF TECHNOLOGY, 21CAKE.COM; SHANGHAI, CHINA – 2014-2015

- Led a technology organization including Dev/QA/IT
- Supervised system architecture re-design project (Server security, Single point of failure)
- Supervised application framework re-design project (PHP)

SENIOR MANAGER OF TECHNOLOGY, <u>ANJUKE.COM</u>; SHANGHAI, CHINA – 2009-2012

- Led "site operation & infrastructure" team
 - Hardware/network/OS maintaining and capacity planning
 - Site status monitoring
 - Database and storage administrating (MySQL)
- Led "kernel development" team
 - Application architecture developing (PHP framework, MogileFS, SolrCloud, DAL)
 - Shard components developing (Login, BBS, API)

STAFF ENGINEER, EBAY.COM; SHANGHAI, CHINA - 2004-2009

- Estimated/Led/Coded projects in search-front-end team (Java)
- Presentation layer developing / page performance optimizing (Javascript, HTML, CSS)
- Conducted Javascript code roll-out

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, EACHNET.COM; SHANGHAI, CHINA – 2000-2004

- Presentation layer developing (PHP)
- Midware developing and administrating (Oracle Tuxedo, C/C++, Linux)
 SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ACER SOFTWARE; SHANGHAI, CHINA 1998-2000
- Windows application developing (C++, MFC, DirectX)
- Multimedia software developing (Flash, Director)

Education

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, USA – M.S. of Computer Science, 2015-Present East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai, China – B.S. of Computer Science, 1994-1998

Skills

- Solid knowledge of programming languages (PHP, NodeJS, Java, C/C++)
- Familiar with front-end technologies (Javascript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap)
- Hands-on experience of database development (MySQL, MongoDB, Solr/Lucence)
- Practical knowledge of version control systems (Git, SVN, ClearCase)
- Practical knowledge of server side technologies and tools (Linux, Bash, AWS, Nginx, MemcacheD, Redis, RabbitMQ, Docker)

Side projects

- RevJS (http://price.liangzhang.io): A website tracking the price change of products on revzilla.com. Technologies involve NodeJS, Solr, Express, EJS, Jenkins and Docker.
- MiniSearch (https://github.com/titanzhang/Liang.MiniSearch): A practice project to build a very basic search engine. Technologies involve Java, Lucene, Spring and Maven.